Ricardo Estevan

restevan@gmail.com

Profile

Organized and effective leadership skills. Proven teamwork and group communication experience.

Skills

Leadership • Teamwork • Team Management • Organizational Development • Microsoft Azure • SharePoint • SharePoint Development • Sharepoint Framework (SPFx) • Azure DevOps

Education

The University of Texas Rio Grande Valley

• Master of Science - MS, Information Technology 2015 - 2017

The University of Texas-Pan American

Bachelor of Business Administration - BBA, Business Administration and Management, General

2008 - 2013

Integrity School

1998 - 2007

Certifications

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals

Experience

SharePoint Administrator

McAllen ISD

Oct 2019 - Present

Designed and developed SharePoint architecture and governance plan for McAllen ISD for more than 100 communication sites and team sites to facilitate team collaboration, simplify project management and streamline document management.

Developed and customized RBAC's, 365 groups, retention policies for SharePoint.

Designed Team sites and Communication sites templates with the usage of SharePoint/Office 365 Dev Patterns & Practices (PnP) Powershell and SPFx Framework to build modern web parts.

Developed custom apps with Power Apps and automated workflows with Power Automate integrated with SharePoint.

Assisted with SharePoint troubleshooting technical issues and conducted virtual trainings to Sharepoint site Admins with best practices for their site.

Google Workspace for Education Administrator

McAllen ISD

Oct 2019 - Present

Manage Google admin console for students domain, users and groups, including security settings, access permissions and device management.

Developed custom LDAP queries to synchronize data with Google Cloud Directory Sync for account provisioning and licensing.

Systems Administrator

CAPA Jul 2017 - Oct 2019

Built data backups and disaster recovery operations plans.

Maintained and administered Command Alkon Server Application server and database server. Develop custom reports with SQL queries

Developed an intranet with communication sites for company's departments. Created team sites templates and managed them with PnP Powershell.Managed document libraries and repositories.

Developed PowerApps custom app for sales team and automated tasks for the company with Power Automate.

Trained and supported SharePoint users and provide SharePoint best practices.